Guide to the School of Nursing, Yale University, Historical Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Students/Alumnae
  - Photographs
    - General, Circa 1970s-2000s (Box 114, Folder 1193-1197)
    - Class photographs
      - Class of 1926 - Class of 1939, Circa 1926-1938, 1956, 1979-1984, 2002 (Box 114, Folder 1198-1210)
      - [Class of 1939?], Circa 1939 (Box 143, Folder 1409)
      - Class of 1941 - Class of 1947 and 1947W, Circa 1941-1947, 1990, and undated (Box 114, Folder 1211-1215)
      - Class of 1948, Circa 1948 (Box 115, Folder 1216)
        - Oversize (Box 143, Folder 1410)
      - Class of 1949 - Class of 1953, Circa 1949-1953, 2003, and undated (Box 115, Folder 1217-1221)
      - Class of 1954, Circa 1954 (Box 115, Folder 1222)
        - Oversize (Box 143, Folder 1411)
        - Oversize (Box 144, Folder 1421)
      - Class of 1955, Undated (Box 115, Folder 1223)
      - Class of 1956, 1986, 2000 (Box 115, Folder 1224)
        - Newsletters (scans) and Introduction for 50th anniversary reunion classbook, 6
      - Class of 1957 - Class of 1984, Circa 1957-2002, and undated (Box 115, Folder 1225-1241)
      - Class of 1985 - Class of 1994, Circa 1982-2001 (Box 116, Folder 1242-1251)
      - Class of 1995 - Class of 2002, Circa 1993-2002 (Box 117, Folder 1252-1259)
    - Clinical, students in, Circa 1920-2000 (Box 117, Folder 1260-1266)
    - Programs
      - Community Health, Circa 1979 and undated (Box 117, Folder 1267)
      - Maternal-Newborn Nursing, Circa 1968-1979, and undated (Box 117, Folder 1268)
      - Medical-Surgical, Circa 1979, and undated (Box 118, Folder 1269)
      - Pediatrics, Circa 1970s (Box 118, Folder 1270)
      - Psychiatric Nursing, Circa 1968-1981 (Box 118, Folder 1271)
      - Public Health, undated (Box 118, Folder 1272)
      - 3-year Program, Circa 1979 (Box 118, Folder 1273)
      - Various, Circa 1970s (Box 118, Folder 1274)
    - Male students, photographs, 1978-1998 (Box 118, Folder 1275)
    - Individuals, photographs
      - Affinito, Eleann, Circa 1941 (Box 137)
      - Affinito, Eleanor A., Circa 1941 (Box 137)
      - Alexander, Florence Mary, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Almas, Rita Ann, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Anderson, Barbara, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Anderson, Maja C., 1945 (Box 137)
      - Apricino, Theresa, Undated (Box 137)
      - Bancroft, Constance Lucille, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Beale, Mary, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Bechdel, Rachel, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Bennett, Helen, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Benua, Mary Ralston, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Berkey, Virginia Florence, Undated (Box 137)
      - Bevans, Frances, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Birdzell, Dorothy, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Bliss, Joan Elizabeth, 1946 (Box 137)
      - Bondareff, Helen E., 1944 (Box 137)
      - Boris, Elizabeth, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Boyle, Betty, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Brawn, Lois, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Buckley, Katherine L., Undated (Box 137)
      - Bulkeley, Anne, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Byer, Muriel, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Cahill, Jean Doe, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Caldwell, Janet, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Caldwell, Mary Jane, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Cervin, Ruth, Undated (Box 137)
      - Clapp, Mary Jeanne, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Clarr, Kathleen Jean, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Clousky (Closky?), Clytie Frances, Undated (Box 137)
      - Cole, Dorothy, 1943 (Box 137)
      - Connor, Doris M., 1944 (Box 137)
      - Cost, Joan Ann, Circa 1965 (Box 137)
      - Creecy, Marcia, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Danforth, Margaret, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Davis, Katherine, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Donohue, Claire, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Droznin, Selma, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Dughi, Catherine E., 1943 (Box 137)
      - Dunn, Margaret Janet, 1945 (Box 137)
      - Eisnn, Aleena, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Epstein, Edna Celia, Undated (Box 137)
      - Field, Margaret M., 1944 (Box 137)
      - Fladager, Lois J., 1944 (Box 137)
      - Ford, Frances C., 1944 (Box 137)
      - Fritz, Marion, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Galantowicz, Wanda R., 1941 (Box 137)
      - Gary, Barbara, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Gibson, Margaret, 1941 (Box 137)
      - Gladding, Anne, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Goodrich, Jean E., 1942 (Box 137)
      - Gorendy, Roslynne, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Grafton, Frances Lucille, 1944 (Box 137)
      - Gray, Betty, 1942 (Box 137)
      - Hall, Marion E., 1944 (Box 138)
      - Hallwich, Doris, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Hampson, Grace, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Hansen, Ethel, 1941 (Box 138)
      - Harris, Florence M., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Haseltine, Margaret, 1941 (Box 138)
      - Hayden, Jane O., 1944 (Box 138)
      - Hibbard, Saisie, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Hicok, Harriet, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Hitchcock, Sally Bradley, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Holladay, Evelyn L., Undated (Box 138)
      - Hooker, Nancy, 1942 (Box 138)
      - House, Hope, 1948 (Box 138)
      - Howe, Virginia, 1941 (Box 138)
      - Howes, Esther G., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Humez, Arvilla L., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Hundstad, Myrtle Bernice, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Hurlin, Barbara S., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Inus, Moe, 1944 (Box 138)
      - James, Britta, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Jund, Janis E., 1944 (Box 138)
      - Judd, Harriet, S., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Keefe, Pauline Julian, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Keuefick, Edith, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Kiersted, Ann B., 1944 (Box 138)
      - Kosters, Betty Ann, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Kummer, Pauline U., 1944 (Box 138)
      - Laffay, Lola M., 1944 (Box 138)
      - LaSeur, Martha H., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Leonard, Claire, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Lewis, Janet, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Logan, Elizabeth, 1937 (Box 138)
      - Lord, Mary Alice, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Louis, Olga, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Lucey, Veronica Mary, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Lyman, Helen, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Lynn, Theresa, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Mahoney, Loretta, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Mankan, Doris Kathryn, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Marshall, Delia, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Martin, Mary, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Matheke, Joan Beatrice, Undated (Box 138)
      - Mattingly, Capitola, 1943 (Box 138)
      - McClure, Catherine Templeton, Undated (Box 138)
      - McCurdy, Lydia, 1943 (Box 138)
      - McEachern, Eula, 1942 (Box 138)
      - McGarry, Dorothy, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Mick, Bertha Genevieve, Undated (Box 138)
      - Miles, Julia V., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Miller, Eleuthera, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Morrison, Elaine, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Morrison-Smith, Marjory, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Morrow, Bess, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Mortimer, Marjorie, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Moss, Margaret, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Mudge, Janet Alice, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Munson, Shirley K., 1944 (Box 138)
      - Neussle, Mary L., 1943 (Box 138)
      - Nichols, Grace, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Nillman, Alice, 1944 (Box 138)
      - Nissley, Mary, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Northrup, Harriett, Undated (Box 138)
      - O'Donoghue, Florence, 1943 (Box 138)
      - Opdycke, Natalie, 1942 (Box 138)
      - Pelikow, Mabel, Undated (Box 139)
      - Perkins, Mildred Ann, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Peterson, Mary Maxine, 1943 (Box 139)
      - Piton, Hope I., 1941 (Box 139)
      - Podrasky, Deborah, Undated (Box 139)
      - Potee, Carol Lois, Undated (Box 139)
      - Purington, Nina, 1942 (Box 139)
      - Rafalowska, Edwiga, 1943 (Box 139)
      - Ricklefs, Betty Ella, 1941 (Box 139)
      - Ritchie, Mary T., 1943 (Box 139)
      - Rogers, Jeanne, 1943 (Box 139)
      - Ross, Alice M., 1941 (Box 139)
      - Roth, Mildred Woodworth, 1942 (Box 139)
      - Rudd, Carolyn Clausen, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Sargent, Sophie, 1943 (Box 139)
      - Schereider, Mathilda E.C., 1943 (Box 139)
      - Schorske, Florence S., 1941 (Box 139)
      - Sealey, Mary Jean, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Severson, Eleanor, 1943 (Box 139)
      - Shaddock, Mildred, 1943 (Box 139)
      - Simpson, Katherine Francis, 1937 (Box 139)
      - Siveke, Marian Elizabeth, 1947 (Box 139)
      - Sjobeck, Mary Alma, 1940 (Box 139)
      - Smith, Antoinette, 1942 (Box 139)
      - Smith, June, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Sprague, Elizabeth Frances, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Stewar, Evelyn M., 1944 (Box 139)
      - Stockbridge, Janet, 1942 (Box 139)
      - Summers, Lisa, Undated (Box 139)
      - Tilghman, Ann Stackhouse, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Van Horn, Elizabeth, 1942 (Box 139)
      - Weaver, Dorothy Ann, 1944 (Box 139)
      - Welch, Caroline G., 1943 (Box 139)
      - Werner, Beatrice Pearl, 1935 (Box 139)
      - Weymouth, Gwendolyn "Flora", 1944 (Box 139)
      - Woodruff, Elizabeth, Undated (Box 139)
      - Worill, Elizabeth Jane, Undated (Box 139)
      - Wright, Elizabeth, 1942 (Box 139)
      - Yalowich, Rhea, 1942 (Box 139)
- Students (Doctoral)
  - Dissertations
  - Publications, 1982-1998 (Box 119, Folder 1281-1283)
- Task Force and Ad Hoc Committee Reports
  Restricted until January 1, 2023.
  - Curriculum Committee to Executive Council, "Yale University School of Nursing: Toward Excellence in Teaching", 1967 (Box 119, Folder 1284)
  - Ethics for publication, recommendations of Ad Hoc Committee on Ethics, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 1285)
  - Faculty Practice Plan Task Force report, 1983 (Box 119, Folder 1286)
  - "Nursing Education at Yale: A Progress Report," Yale Medicine, 1969 (Box 119, Folder 1287)
  - "Sexual Harassment Task Force, Report to the Dean", 1987 (Box 119, Folder 1288)
  - Triple Commitment, ad hoc committee report, 1972 (Box 119, Folder 1289)
- Taylor, Euphemia Jane
  - Biographical materials, Circa 1937-1986, and undated (Box 119, Folder 1290)
  - Copies of documents, photographs, and articles from Taylor Collection, Manuscripts and Archives, Circa 1934-1966 (Box 119, Folder 1291)
  - Correspondence
    - General, Circa 1936-1968, 2004, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1292-1293)
    - With Mary Cloud Bean, 1935, 2002 (Box 120, Folder 1294)
  - Death
    - General, 1970 (Box 120, Folder 1295)
    - Letters of condolences upon her death in Hamilton, Ontario, additional letters received by Dean Taylor's sister, with photographs and news clipping, 1962, 1970, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1296-1297)
  - International Council of Nurses, Circa 1940-1947, 1965, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1298)
  - Photographs, Circa 1894-1966, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1299)
    - Oversize (Box 143, Folder 1412)
  - Publications, 1938-1947 (Box 120, Folder 1300)
  - Red Cross activities, 1939-1959 (Box 120, Folder 1301)
- Uniforms
  - Caps and miscellaneous, with photograph and negatives, 1873, 1943, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1302)
  - Connecticut Training School for Nurses, 1875-1923, Circa 1920-1939, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1303)
  - Correspondence, orders, invoice, Circa 1926-1948 (Box 120, Folder 1304)
  - Photographs, Circa 1930s-1940s (Box 120, Folder 1305)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital, Circa 1930s, and undated (Box 120, Folder 1306)
    - Oversize, 1954 (Box 143, Folder 1413)
  - Yale University School of Nursing uniform information, Circa 1926-1956 (Box 120, Folder 1307)
- Union, Local 34
  - General, 1984-1985 (Box 120, Folder 1308)
    - Phil Donohue show on Local 34 v.Yale, [1984]; 1 (Box 211)
  - 2nd Contract, 1987-1990 (Box 120, Folder 1309)
- University
  - Campus of Yale, booklets and photographs, Circa 1969-1992 (Box 120, Folder 1310)
    - Oversize, Undated (Box 143, Folder 1414)
  - News clippings on presidents, women, labor strike, 1931-1959 (Box 120, Folder 1311)
  - Presidents of Yale, photographs, Undated (Box 120, Folder 1312)
- Visiting Nurse Association
  - Archive copies, 1917-1927, 1994 (Box 121, Folder 1313)
  - History, photographs and news clippings, 1954-1964 (Box 121, Folder 1314)
- Visitors
  - Photographs, 1977-1999 (Box 121, Folder 1315-1316)
  - Registration cards, Circa 1920s-1960s (Box 141)
- Wald, Florence Sophie
  - Biographical, Circa 1958-1998 (Box 121, Folder 1317)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 121, Folder 1318)
  - Honorary degree, University of Bridgeport, 1967 (Box 121, Folder 1319)
  - Photographs, Circa 1959-1998, and undated (Box 121, Folder 1320)
  - Professional activities, news clippings and releases, Circa 1957-1999 (Box 121, Folder 1321)
  - Publications, speeches, papers, 1959-1980 (Box 121, Folder 1322)
- Wartime nursing
  - Miscellaneous orders, bulletins, information, Circa 1942-1945 (Box 121, Folder 1323)
  - Newsletters
    - 39th General Headlines, 1942 (Box 121, Folder 1324)
    - National Nursing Council for War Service, Nursing News, and Professional Nursing, Circa 1943-1945 (Box 121, Folder 1325)
  - Nurses' draft, 1942-1945 (Box 121, Folder 1326)
  - Nurses in the Navy, Circa 1942-1944 (Box 121, Folder 1327)
  - Nurses in the Navy, "Saltwater Taffy" newsletter, 1942 (Box 143, Folder 1415)
  - Nurses overseas (Pacific, Europe, Africa), photographs and news clippings, Circa 1942-1946, 1982, and undated (Box 121, Folder 1328)
  - Nurses' recruitment efforts, 1940-1945 (Box 121, Folder 1329)
  - Nurses' reminiscences, vignettes, humor, tales, Circa 1942-1946, and undated (Box 122, Folder 1330)
  - Nursing shortage, 1942-1945 (Box 122, Folder 1331)
  - Nursing, training, and miscellaneous news articles, Circa 1942-1945 (Box 122, Folder 1332)
  - Volunteering, 1945 (Box 122, Folder 1333)
  - Yale nurses join up, Circa 1940-1944 (Box 122, Folder 1334)
  - Yale University Military Hospital Number 39
    - Mobilizes, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 122, Folder 1335)
    - Photographs, Circa 1940s (Box 144, Folder 1421)
    - Visit to New Zealand, photographs, 1944 (Box 146)
- Women at Yale, 1981 (Box 122, Folder 1336)
- Yale Medical Center, photographs, Circa 1930s-1980s, and undated (Box 122, Folder 1337)
- Yale Medical School faculty, photographs, Circa 1970s, and undated (Box 122, Folder 1338)
- Yale-New Haven Hospital
  - Alling, Dorothy, with photograph, 1984, and undated (Box 122, Folder 1339)
  - Grace-New Haven Community Hospital
    - Agreements between the General Hospital Society of Connecticut, Yale University, and Grace Hospital, 1980 (Box 122, Folder 1341)
    - News clippings, 1940-1962 (Box 122, Folder 1342)
    - Nurse staffing, reports, correspondence, Circa 1937-1949, and undated (Box 122, Folder 1343)
    - United for Health, consolidation and expansion, 1945 (Box 143, Folder 1416)
  - Grace School of Nursing, 1957, 1959 (Box 122, Folder 1344)
  - History, photographs, Circa 1931-1943, and undated (Box 122, Folder 1345)
  - News, 1975-1980 (Box 122, Folder 1346)
  - Photographs, Circa 1920s-1930, and undated (Box 123, Folder 1347)
    - Oversize, unidentified, Undated (Box 143, Folder 1417)
  - Rooming-in
    - Jackson, Dr. Edith B., photographs and article, 1951, 1959, and undated (Box 123, Folder 1348)
    - Mothers, fathers, babies, photographs, 1947, 1951-1952, and undated (Box 123, Folder 1349)
    - Nursing care, bedside, photographs, 1947, 1954, 1999, and undated (Box 123, Folder 1350)
    - "Start of YNHH (Yale-New Haven Hospital) Rooming-In Program", 1948; 1 (Box 212)
    - Photographs and article, 1947, and undated (Box 123, Folder 1351)
    - Photographs for Life Magazine, Circa 1940 (Box 143, Folder 1418)
    - Rooms and facilities, photographs, 1949, 1951, and undated (Box 123, Folder 1352)
- Computer files, 2008-A-147 (Box 214)
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software